THUNDER GATE
Processed by 繁化姬 dict-40c95aa0-r1041 @ 2023/12/04 23:54:11 | https://zhconvert.org
SEPTEMBER 12, 2034 TEN YEARS SINCE THE CALAMITY
（2034年9月12日） （大灾害过后十年）
Five years ago,
五年前
we made our living in the Electro-Kart Racing industry.
我们在电动卡丁车赛车界讨生活
TEAM FUNAYAMA - KIRIKO TAKEHAYA
（舟山队，竹早桐子）
Come on, Ozaki!
拜托你了，尾崎
Katayama!
片山
Kiriko!
桐子
-Come back! -Stop there!
-等等 -别跑
Takehaya?
竹早？
Damn it.
可恶
Don't chase them too far! Haruki!
别追了，春希
Let's get the hell outta here.
我们闪人吧
But that little brat has seen our faces.
但那家伙见到我们的长相了
Looks like you've been looking after our young lad, huh?
看来你们很照顾我底下的年轻人呢
Robin! These guys have been making fake tickets!
露敏，这些人在制造假门票
TENGOKU-DAIMAKYO
《天国大魔境》 （推动发车）
Did you think you could kill me with a tiny scrap of metal?
凭一个小小的金属片就想杀了我？
Haruki, when you fight your enemies, you don't need to stare into their eyes.
春希，跟敌人对打时 不需要向他们干瞪眼
Glaring is just something cowards do
瞪眼是懦夫的行为
when they want to get away with only intimidating their opponents.
他们只是想用这种方式吓跑敌人
Avoid the eyes, and concentrate on the collar instead.
避开眼神接触，把视线专注在领口
Then focus on the ground, check how it feels beneath your feet.
然后再看向地面，确定是否站得稳
Those who do nothing but look at their opponents, lose.
那些只会紧盯着对手的人，准输无疑
Let's hand these guys over to the boss.
把这些人交给老大吧
Nice going, Haruki.
干得好，春希
If you want something, just ask me.
想要什么东西直接跟我说
We're back!
我们回来了
What meat is that?
那是什么肉？
Monkey, crow and mouse. I think.
应该是猴子、乌鸦和老鼠吧
Wow, cool jacket!
好酷的外套
Robin gave it to me.
露敏送我的
It's a little baggy.
有点太大了
He'll grow into it quickly, though!
他很快就会长高了
Now I want something too.
害我也想要礼物了啦
How about trousers? Bet they'll fit if you cut them in half.
裤子好吗？但得把裤子剪一半 你穿起来才不会太长
My legs are not that short!
我的腿才没有那么短
I'm hungry.
我饿了
Sis, you're back!
姐，你回来咯
Where did you finish?
你的战迹如何？
Didn't you see? I was disqualified. I fell out of my kart.
你们没看到吗？被取消资格，我摔车了
What? Did you hurt yourself?
你受伤了吗？
No, I'm okay. The other drivers went around me.
没有啦，我没事，其他赛车手 都从我身边绕过去了
Right, Doc?
对吧，医生？
That's so dangerous. You gotta be more careful!
太危险了，你得小心一点才行
You really should drive more safely.
赛车的时候要注意一点
I get it, I get it.
我知道啦，我知道啦
REPORTS OF SPECTATORS GOING MISSING
（失踪观众报告）
Oh, yeah, Kiriko.
对了，桐子
I attached a flash to my camera.
我帮相机装了闪光灯
Let's take some new photos to sell.
我们照几张新的相片来卖吧
Take one of me and Doc, then.
帮我跟医生照一张吧
I'm good, thanks.
我不用了啦，谢谢
Ready!
准备好
-Time to go. -Okay.
-该走了 -好
Thanks, Doc.
谢谢，医生
Haruki, I heard the doc is researching "Man-eaters,"
春希，我听说医生正在研究食人者
and even experimenting on humans.
甚至还进行了人体实验
Robin's investigating at the moment.
露敏目前正在调查
But it'd be better if Kiriko didn't get too close to him.
但桐子最好不要跟他走得太近
CURRENTLY IN USE BY FUNAYAMA ORPHANAGE
（目前由船山孤儿院使用中）
KIRIKO AND HARUKI TAKEHAYA
（竹早桐子和春希）
Haruki, aren't you cold?
春希，你不冷吗？
No, you?
不会，你呢？
Freezing.
冷死了
Wanna get in here?
那你想过来这里吗？
You're actually getting in?
你还真的要过来哦？
What's happening?
怎么回事？
There's a Man-eater in the third district!
三区出现了食人者
It's not coming this way, so go back to sleep.
它不是朝这里过来，快回去睡觉
-Let's go, Robin! -Coming!
-我们要走了，露敏 -来了
Are you going?
你要去吗？
It's okay, I have the gun that I made,
不用担心，我有自制手枪
and I want to be helpful to Robin.
我想助露敏一臂之力
If I think about those days…
那些陈年往事，现在回想起来
they seem like heaven to me now.
仿佛就像在天国一样
KIRIKO AND HARUKI
《桐子和春希》
Not bad.
还不赖
You killed a Man-eater with that weapon last week?
你上个礼拜用那把武器杀了一个食人者？
Yeah.
对
I'm not playing around! I told you not to come. It's dangerous!
我不是在开玩笑的 我叫你别来，很危险耶
I made Robin angry, though.
但露敏被我气炸了
Ten years ago, Robin had a sister my age.
十年前，露敏有个跟我同年龄的妹妹
He lost her in the Great Disaster.
但她死于那场大灾难
Since then, he's been overprotective.
从此之后，他就变得有点过度保护
Wait! What time is it?
等等，现在几点了？
Which watch is right again?
哪支表才是正确的？
-That one. -Twenty after two.
-那支 -2点20分了
I have to go! Sis's race starts at three!
我得走了，姐在3点有比赛
See you later!
再见咯
Robin might be overprotective,
露敏或许是保护过头
but that guy is obsessed with his sister.
但那家伙简直有恋姐情结
Right?
可不是吗？
SEPTEMBER 20, 2034 TEN YEARS SINCE THE CALAMITY
（2034年9月20日） （大灾害过后十年）
Okay, just made it.
好险，刚好赶上
Help!
来人啊
There's a Man-eater at the end of the track!
赛道终点有只食人者
It can turn invisible, same as the one before!
它会隐形，跟之前那只一样
All karts are off at once!
赛车手已全数出发
What kind of race will it be today?
今天的赛况会如何呢？
Sis.
姐
The Man-eater's gone into the arcade.
食人者进入了商店街
It's probably seven or eight minutes until the karts get there.
离赛车抵达终点的时间大概有七八分钟
I'll drive it away.
我会赶走它
I know I can do it.
我知道我办得到
After the long straight,
经过了长距离的直线赛道之后
karts eight, three and four round the second corner.
八号、三号和四号赛车来到了第二弯道
It's a crash for two and five, a spin that will set them way back!
二号和五号撞车了 原地打滑让他们大幅落后
The rest are off towards Sensoji.
其余赛车手则冲向浅草寺
Number four, Takehaya, you pulled that off well!
四号车手竹早，那招太漂亮了
-Goddamn it! -Nice one, Kiriko!
-不是吧 -厉害哦，桐子
Where is it?
它在哪里？
Has it left the course?
它离开赛道了吗？
Got it!
逮到它了
Unbelievable, it barely hurt it.
岂有此理，它根本毫发无伤
Finally, got a hit.
终于刺中它了
My arm!
我的手臂
Let me go!
放开我
It's eating me.
它正在吃我
Robin, help me!
露敏，救我
Takehaya's in the lead,
竹早目前领先
exiting the third corner towards the arcade.
离开了第三弯道，朝商店街冲过去
They'll be momentarily out of sight.
转播会中断一会儿
The Asakusa Race Association
浅草赛车协会
is in the process of arranging for cameras to be installed throughout the course.
目前正在安排于整条赛道加装摄像头
If you can offer such a service, then by all means, please get in touch.
如果你能提供这项服务 请不用客气，尽速与他们联系
Stop! There's a Man-eater! Call the race off!
停车，那里有只食人者，比赛取消
Go back and tell the headquarters.
回去通知总部
Okay.
好的
Haruki?
春希？
Haruki!
春希
Give him back.
把他还给我
Let him go!
放开他
Haru… No.
春…不要
It can't be.
不可能的
Somebody! Anybody, quickly!
来人啊，救命啊，快来人啊
Help!
救命啊
Sis…
姐…
She's so close.
我们靠得好近
CURRENTLY IN USE BY FUNAYAMA ORPHANAGE
（目前由船山孤儿院使用中）
Everyone…
每个人…
Sis?
姐？
My head…
我的头…
It's so hot.
好烫
Sis.
姐
Sis?
姐？
Sis!
姐！
Takehaya has regained consciousness!
竹早恢复意识了
Apparently, there's another Man-eater in the area,
显然这区还有另一只食人者
and a child is dead.
死了一个孩子
That's horrifying.
太可怕了
Excuse me.
不好意思
Why…
怎么会…
Si-- Sis?
姐？
Me?
我？
The patient, she--
这位病人，她…
Takehaya!
竹早
You shouldn't be walking yet!
你还不能下床
Stop! I'm Haruki!
住口，我是春希
-Where's Sis? -Get a tranquilizer!
-姐她人呢？ -去拿镇静剂
-Going! -I want my sister! Sis!
-快去 -我要我姐姐，姐！
-You need to calm down. -Sis! Sis!
-你得冷静 -姐，姐
I think that the shock of her brother's death
应该是弟弟过世让她太震惊了
has led her to believe that she is her brother.
导致她认为自己是弟弟
The poor girl.
可怜的孩子
The doctor.
医生…
What did the doctor do?
医生做了什么？
He must know what happened.
他一定知道发生了什么事
Where's the doctor?
医生人呢？
After giving you both medical attention, the doctor left town.
治疗你们过后，医生就离开这里了
You were both brought here on the verge of death.
你们姐弟当初被送来这里的时候 都已经奄奄一息了
What happened to your brother is incredibly upsetting,
发生在你弟弟身上的事实在是很不幸
but no matter what treatment we used,
但不管我们当初用了什么样的治疗方式
without the doctor, I believe you would both be dead.
没有医生的话 我认为你们两个都活不下来
--SOJI HOSPITAL
（草寺医院）
I don't understand.
我不明白
Last time I saw her,
我上一次见到姐的时候
she was crying, but definitely alive.
她正在哭，但肯定还活着
Was she eaten by the Man-eater?
她被食人者吃掉了吗？
One thing is undeniable.
有一点是无法否认的
I am definitely still Haruki.
我绝对是春希
The proof of that
证据就是
is the sorrow splintering through me at the news of my sister's death,
在我听到姐姐的死讯时，我感到伤心欲绝
and the occasional faint solace
但时不时会感到有点欣慰
of having inherited the body of someone I love.
那是来自于继承了我心爱的人的身体
By the time my sister's wounds had healed, and I could start to move her body again,
经过了将近四个月的时间 我姐姐的伤口才完全愈合
nearly four months had passed.
我也能开始自由运用她的身体
Robin must be investigating what that doctor was up to.
露敏一定在调查那名医生做了什么
I'm sure he will be able to figure it out.
我肯定他一定能够查明真相
He'll be able to tell me why I have become my sister,
他将能够告诉我为什么我变成了我姐姐
and why she had to die.
为什么她必须得死
ASAKUSA RACE ASSOCIATION HEADQUARTERS
（浅草赛车协会）
Excuse me.
不好意思
I'm hoping to see Robin Inazaki from the Asakusa Race Association--
我想拜访浅草赛车协会的稻崎露敏
That's not possible.
你别想见到他了
Sometime around September last year,
我肯定他在去年9月的某一天
I'm pretty sure he was murdered.
被杀害了
There was an increase in disappearances around here last year.
这附近在去年爆增了多起失踪人口事件
Seems he got tangled up in trying to investigate.
他似乎因为想查明真相而惹祸上身
Then, just like that, he ended up disappearing too.
然后他也跟其他人一样消失了
Ken! Ran!
健、兰
Director!
园长
Anyone!
有人在吗？
Please! What happened to the orphanage that was here?
不好意思，原本在这里的 孤儿院发生了什么事？
-It was moved elsewhere. -What?
他们搬走了
Their highest earning racer died…
他们最会赚钱的赛车手过世了…
REPORTS OF SPECTATORS GOING MISSING
（失踪观众报告）
…and the leader went missing.
队长也失踪了
I expect with all the bad luck, they gave up on this town.
我想因为不幸意外接踵而来 让他们放弃了这个城镇
Sis.
姐
Robin.
露敏
Then, just like that, he ended up disappearing too.
然后他也跟其他人一样消失了
The leader went missing.
队长也失踪了
"Missing"?
「失踪」？
"Disappeared"?
「消失」？
There isn't actually any proof that Robin is dead.
并没有任何证据证明露敏死了
There's no way Robin can be dead.
露敏绝对不可能死了
He must be alive somewhere.
他一定还活着
The doctor.
医生
The doctor has the answer to everything.
找到医生，一切就能真相大白
Where Robin is, why my sister is dead
露敏身在何处，我姐姐为什么会过世
and why I'm living inside her body!
还有为什么我会在姐姐的身体里
TRIP GUARD
（旅人保镖）
PROTECTION FROM WILD ANIMALS, BANDITS AND MAN-EATERS - KIRUKO
（免于野生动物 强盗和食人者的侵害，贵留子）
After that, I lived in various towns, searching for the two of them,
之后我开始穿梭于不同的城镇 找寻他们俩的踪迹
accepting requests, and doing everything by myself.
接受请托，一切靠自己
Four years later, I met you in Nakano.
四年后，我在中野遇见了你
DO NOT ENTER
（禁止进入）
It's the first time I've told anyone that.
这些事我从来没向任何人说过
I want to check something with you.
我想跟你确认一件事
Would it be better if I stopped calling you "Sis"?
我是不是不该再叫你「姐」了？
That?
这个哦？
Don't worry about it.
别想那么多
You've been calling me that for a month, pretty sure we're both used to it now.
你已经叫我姐叫了一个月了 我们彼此应该也都习惯了
Well, there you go. You'll have to think of me as a man now.
但你提醒了我 从现在起你该把我当成男人看待了
I can't wrap my mind around it just like that!
我没办法就这样说变就变啦
Anyway, you're getting pretty good looking.
总之，你也算是个美少年
I'm sure you'll meet someone more appropriate soon.
我肯定你很快就会遇上合适的对象
I won't find a girl I get along with this well.
我不可能找到一个 跟你一样这么合拍的女孩
That's because we're both guys.
那是因为我们都是男生啦
So the photo of Jane Inamura, right?
那么，那是稻村珍的相片是吗？
It's Robin Inazaki.
是稻崎露敏啦
What do you think about him?
你是怎么看待他的？
Well,
这个嘛
we grew up in the same house, so I guess he's like family.
我们从小一起长大，他就像个家人吧
But he's also a close friend.
但他也是我很亲近的朋友
I suppose I admire him.
我想我很崇拜他吧
Because we're both guys! I look up to him.
因为我们都是男生，我很景仰他
You still don't get it, do you?
你还是没弄懂，对吧？
What do you expect when you tell someone something like that?
你告诉了我这些事 你期望我能有什么反应？
Maybe a good night's sleep will sort your head out.
或许好好睡一觉会让你头脑清醒
Fine.
好吧
Maybe when I wake up this will all turn out to be a dream.
或许我醒来之后会发现原来是梦一场
What now? What's the racket for?
怎么了？为什么这么吵？
What is it?
怎么回事？
There was a huge fish outside the window.
窗外有一条超大的鱼
A fish?
一条鱼？
The window is wet, even though it's not raining.
窗户湿湿的，但是没下雨
Strange.
很奇怪
Maru, go and tell the captain to keep an eye--
小丸，通知船长小心…
A Man-eater.
食人者
Is it a baby?
是个婴儿吗？
Can I have it?
可以给我吗？
I promised to give this one to Tokio. You can have the next.
我答应时男这张要给他，下一张再给你
Sounds good to me!
太棒了
I like your weird drawing.
我好喜欢你怪怪的画风
You think it's weird?
你觉得怪怪的哦？
Obviously! Proper babies--
当然啊，正常的婴儿…
Climbing on tables is forbidden, Kuku.
玖玖，禁止爬上桌子
Stop annoying Kona and come with me.
别打扰小奈了，你跟我来
Hey--
唉哟
If you're going to be nasty about them, then stop asking for Kona's drawings!
如果你要批评小奈的画 就别再叫他把画送给你了
I was saying they were good!
我说的是好话啊
Besides, I've seen one. A real baby.
我见过一个真正的婴儿
Real babies don't have faces.
真正的婴儿没有脸
Want to go and see it?
你想看吗？